Hlulani Sithole

Sunnyside, Pretoria 0002 Cell: 060 544 0881

Email: <u>u21685224@tuks.co.za</u>

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/hlulani-sithole-27834a262

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Currently in the 2nd year of my Bachelor of Commerce degree, specialising in Statistics and Data Science at the University of Pretoria. My secondary studies, complemented by a background in Computer Applications Technology, have equipped me with the necessary knowledge to manage the requirements of the Student IT lab assistant position which is entirely in line with my skill set:

- Applying a systematic, results-driven approach to task execution to ensure the timely provisioning of basic hardware, software, and printing support; in addition to maintaining a clean and organised environment.
- Knowledgeable in the ethical and fair use of information resources.
- Demonstrated knowledge in computer troubleshooting.

EDUCATION

2021-Current: Bachelor of Commerce in Statistics & Data Science, University of Pretoria

Majors: Applications in Data Science(73%), Macroeconomics(84%), Microeconomics (70%),

Statistics (53%)

2016-2020: National Senior Certificate, Princess Park Secondary & College

Subjects: Computer Applications Technology (72%), Mathematics (70%),

Physical Sciences (65%),

WORK EXPERIENCE

2022- Current : Mathematics Tutor, Freelancer (part-time)

- · Assisting learner with maths home-work and preparation for tests
- Reviewing classroom or curricula topics and assignments

2019-2020: Teacher's assistant, Volunteering

- Assisting with the setup of events
- Entertaining the audience with Tsonga cultural dance

ACHIEVEMENTS & LEADERSHIP

2023: Golden Key Award, University of Pretoria

- Top 15% of the Economics faculty
- Recognition of leadership

2022: Moshal Scholarship, Martin Moshal

- The scholarship is awared based on leadership and academic merit
- MP Scholars demonstrate: the tenacity, ambition, resilience, and commitment to succeed, despite the considerable challenges that they may have faced.

TRAINING

2023

- Short course in Generative AI, Microsoft & LinkedIn Learning
- Ready for Work Program (in progress), University of Pretoria
- SpeakOutUP, University of Pretoria

SKILLS

Languages

English (fluent), Xitsonga (fluent)

Computer literacy

- Basic knowledge of Hardware and Software
- Proficient in Microsoft skills including MS Word, Excel and PowerPoint
- Data Analysis, R Programming & SQL

Power Skills

- Communication, Conflict Resolution, Problem-solving, highly motivated, Team-work
- Very organized, Professional and high level of confidentiality

REFERENCES

Miss Malatji

CAT Teacher, Princess Park Secondary & College

Cell: +27 (0) 67 1646 646 Email: phileh2@gmail.com